Egypt
Marist College
Egypt
1789 1984
Marist Archives and Special Collections 3399 North Road, Poughkeepsie, New York 12601
Lowell Thomas
2.1.1.2.1.3
1203 Linear feet
Items in this collection do not circulate and may be used in-house only.
Glass Plate Negatives; Egypt
- Lowell Thomas Papers
  - Graphic Material, 2
    - Photographs, 2.1
      - Glass Plate Negatives, 2.1.1
        - Lowell Thomas, 2.1.1.2
          - Indexed Photographs, 2.1.1.2.1
            - Egypt, 2.1.1.2.1.3
                - American Diplomatic Agency, Cairo, 1918; 1 (Box 1269)
                5x7
                film
                - Colonel Davis, Cairo, 1918; 2
                - Gary, Knabenshue, and Colonel Davis, 1918; 3
                - Camouflaged ship in Suez Canal, 1918; 4
                - Pompey’s Pillar and mini replica of Sphinx, 1918; 5
                - Many sailboats unloading supplies at Suez Canal, 1918; 6
                - Sailboat in Suez Canal at sunset, 1918; 7
                - Soldiers in front of ancient Sweet Water Canal of Pharaohs, 1918; 8
                - Dredging canal, 1918; 9
                - Great Pyramid of Giza and Sphinx, 1918; 10
                4x5
                - Two Egyptian girls with water bottles, Great Pyramid of Giza in distance, 1918; 11
                - British soldier on donkey at Sphinx with Great Pyramid of Giza in background, 1918; 12
                - Three pyramids of Giza at sunset, 1918; 13
                - Man standing at Sphinx and Great Pyramid of Giza at sunset, smaller pyramid in background, 1918; 14
                - View of three pyramids from airplane (aerial view), 1918; 15
                - Nile River from airplane (aerial view), 1918; 16
                - Airplane and corner of Cairo from air (aerial view), 1918; 17
                - Nile River and Heliopolis from airplane (aerial view), 1918; 18
                - Airplane on the tail end of another (aerial view), 1918; 19
                - Barracks of Egyptian army from airplane (aerial view), 1918; 20
                - View of Egypt from airplane, best view (aerial view), 1918; 21
                - View of Egypt, Heliopolis from airplane (aerial view), 1918; 22
                - Sweetened water seller on street in Cairo, 1918; 23
                - Stern wheeler and sailboat on Nile, 1918; 24
                - Egyptian smoking a nargileh, 1918; 25
                - Lowell Thomas on camel talking to Egyptian boy, 1918; 26
                3x4.5
                - Lowell Thomas on camel paying Egyptian in front of Sphinx, Great Pyramid of Giza in background, 1918; 27
                - Lowell Thomas on camel paying Egyptian in front of Sphinx, Great Pyramid of Giza in background, 1918; 28
                - Lowell Thomas on camel in front of Sphinx with hat pushed back, Great Pyramid of Giza in background, 1918; 29
                - Cheops pyramid from airplane (aerial view), 1918; 30
                - Cheops pyramid from airplane (aerial view), 1918; 31
                - Hotel at Heliopolis, Royal Air Force Headquarters, 1918; 32
                - Sphinx and Great Pyramid of Giza with crowd in front, 1918; 33
                - Pyramid, palm trees, and men sitting in the foreground, 1918; 34
                - Sphinx between two pyramids of Giza, 1918; 35
                - Pyramid and double palm trees in center, 1918; 36
                - Three pyramids of Giza and two palm trees on left, 1918; 37
                - Three pyramids of Giza and two palm trees on left, 1918; 38
                - Three pyramids at sunset, 1918; 39
                - Three pyramids at sunset, 1918; 40
                - Duke of Connaught and Arabs at Cheops pyramid (Great Pyramid of Giza), 1918; 41
                - Lowell Thomas and two officers in front of Sphinx, Great Pyramid of Giza in background, 1918; 42
                - Pyramids, palm trees, old Arab in foreground, 1918; 43
                - General headquarters, Hotel Savoy, 1918; 44
                - Pyramids, trolley line, men on donkeys at sunset, 1918; 45
                - Three pyramids of Giza and Sphinx, silhouette, 1918; 46
                - Cairo, largest mosque, people and carts in street, 1918; 47
                - Sphinx and Great Pyramid of Giza, 1918; 48
                - Sultan’s bodyguard, 1918; 49
                - Veiled girl, full length, 1918; 50
                - Sphinx head, 1918; 51
                - Lowell Thomas and Egyptian cobbler, 1918; 52
                - Three Armenian children, 1918; 53
                - Four little Armenian children, 1918; 54
                - Cross looking little Armenian girl with scraggly hair, 1918; 55
                - Group of Armenian women, 1918; 56
                - Two Armenian men and old woman, 1918; 57
                - Old Armenian, 1918; 58
                - Armenian child, 1918; 59
                - Two Australian soldiers watch Armenian women sew at a refugee camp, 1918; 60
                - Model ships, 1918; 61
                - Model ships, 1918; 62
                - Suez from water tower, 1918; 63
                - Indians eating on street lined with tents, 1918; 64
                - Indian with pigtail, 1918; 65
                - Indian in profile wearing headdress, 1918; 66
                - Red Cross ship, 1918; 67
                - Two Indian men, 1918; 68
                - Street through Indian camp, ship in background, 1918; 69
                - Sailboat and steamer in Suez Canal, 1918; 70
                - Woman with water jar, canal, 1918; 71
                - Sailboat in Suez Canal at sunset, best view, 1918; 72
                - Well of Moses in Sinai Desert, 1918; 73
                - Well of Moses, Harry Chase and two others standing near edge, 1918; 74
                - Three soldiers in desert trench near Well of Moses, 1918; 75
                - Well of Moses, Lowell Thomas and three soldiers eating lunch, 1918; 76
                - British soldier lying under palm tree, 1918; 77
                - Well of Moses, distant, 1918; 78
                - Trench of Well of Moses, distant, 1918; 79
                - Winding trench, soldier in center, 1918; 80
                - Soldiers sitting at table in front of Y.M.C.A. tent, woman standing at center, Suez, close-up, 1918; 81
                - Soldiers standing in front of Y.M.C.A. tents, Suez, 1918; 82
                - Pyramid, double palm tree, no people, 1918; 83
                - Naked child, 1918; 84
                - British soldier putting head through palm fronds, 1918; 85
                - Second Black Watch at Ismalia, 1918; 86
                - Saladin’s citadel, Cairo, 1918; 87
                - Oldest Mosque in Cairo, 1918; 88
                - Captain Guy Smith and Captain Mead standing in front of seaplane [Port Said?], 1918; 89
                - Guy Smith’s seaplane, 1918; 90
                - Maldives Hut, officer in pith helmet in foreground, 1918; 91
                - Lowell Thomas on donkey, palace of governor in Khartown, 1918; 1 (Box 1270)
                - Sudan, holy man, 1918; 2
                - Sudan, holy man, 1918; 3
                - Sudanese soldier saluting, 1918; 4
                - Sudanese soldier saluting, 1918; 5
                - Men sitting on street, man standing with basket on head, 1918; 6
                - People on street, woman eating, 1918; 7
                - Men on street, man with large bags, 1918; 8
                3.5x5
                - Men and woman talking on street, people in background, 1918; 9
                - Group of men talking, 1918; 10
                - Statue of Charles George Gordon on camel, 1918; 11
                - Statue of Charles George Gordon, 1918; 12
                - A Sudan train, 1918; 13
                - A Sudan train, 1918; 14
                3.5x4.5
                - View from airplane [Port Said?] (aerial view), 1918; 15
                6x7
                - Port Said entrance to canal, view from top of lighthouse, 1918; 16
                - Port Said entrance to canal, view from top of light house [different time of day], 1918; 17
                - Egyptian soldier approaching statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps in distances, best view, 1918; 18
                - Statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps, child approaching camera in foreground, 1918; 19
                - Statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps, side view of Egyptian policeman in foreground, 1918; 20
                - Statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps, Egyptian policeman in foreground looking at camera, 1918; 21
                - Statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps, close-up, best picture, 1918; 22
                - Statue of Ferdinand de Lessops, close-up, fair only, 1918; 23
                - View of Cairo, two mosques, 1918; 24
                - View from airplane of unidentified city (aerial view), 1918; 25
                - Walled compound [?], 1918; 26
                - Lowell Thomas and officers on camels next to Arabs in front of Sphinx and Great Pyramid of Giza, 1918; 27
                - Palm trees, soldiers in foreground, 1918; 28
                - Bearded man with basket on shoulder, 1918; 29
                - Sinking ship next to two others [Port Said?], 1918; 30
                - Sinking Ship [Port Said?], 1918; 31
                - Close-up view of sinking ship [Port Said?], 1918; 32
                - Ships docked [Port Said?], 1918; 33
                - View from ship [Port Said?], 1918; 34
                - View of ship from another [Port Said?], 1918; 35
                - Captain Guy Smith and Captain Mead sitting in seaplane [Port Said?], 1918; 36
                - Captain Guy Smith and Captain Mead sitting in seaplane [Port Said?], 1918; 37
                - Captain Guy Smith or Captain Mead in seaplane [Port Said?], 1918; 38
                - Two officers and one man dressed in civilian clothes [Port Said?], 1918; 39
                - Smiling man with hat [Port Said?], 1918; 40
                - Man in hat, distant city in background, 1918; 41
                - Street scene, palms, 1918; 42
                - Cattle, sign for “Thomas Cook and Sons, Egypt Limited” in distance, 1918; 43
                - People with camels, Nile River, Great Pyramid of Giza in distance, 1918; 44
                - Group of people with three camels, pyramid in background, 1918; 45
                - Great Pyramid of Giza from airplane (aerial view), 1918; 46
                - Many camels, 1918; 47
                - Man walking with camel, leveling road, 1918; 48